<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-04-30T02:44:08+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Atrion’s Blog</title><subtitle>A personal public journal and blog.</subtitle><author><name>atrion</name></author><entry><title type="html">Getting Back Into Things</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Getting-Back-Into-Things/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting Back Into Things" /><published>2025-04-30T02:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-30T02:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Getting-Back-Into-Things</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Getting-Back-Into-Things/"><![CDATA[<p>Today felt like one of those quiet resets, not because anything grand happened, but because a few things finally moved forward.</p>

<p>For one, I got back on a bike again. It’s been years. My legs remembered how (mostly), but that seat has no mercy. Felt like I pedaled for five minutes and had earned an ice pack and a nap. But it’s a start. The plan isn’t distance or speed right now it’s <em>consistency</em>.</p>

<p>I also took some time to clean up this site, just a bunch of small updates here and there. Little style tweaks, layout fixes, improved tagging. I want this to be something I can build on slowly, not something that gets away from me like blogs in the past.</p>

<p>That goes for my Obsidian vault too. It got overgrown, bloated with folders and tags and items I wasn’t really using. Today was the start of a trim-back. Reorganizing and deleting. I’m trying to return it to a place where I can write and reflect, not just manage a maze.</p>

<p>To balance things out, I started a rewatch of <em>Doctor Who,</em> back to the Ninth Doctor and all the leather-jacket nostalgia. There’s something nice about returning to stories that once felt like home.</p>

<p>And of course, I kept up with my Bible reading schedule. Today’s portion was:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Leviticus 23</strong> About the feasts of the Lord, which were always more than calendar events, they were reminders of who He is.</li>
  <li><strong>Psalm 80</strong> A cry for restoration, written from the ache of distance and the hope of mercy.</li>
  <li><strong>Matthew 21</strong> The entry into Jerusalem and the clearing of the temple; a shift in tone and pace as the cross drew closer.</li>
</ul>

<p>Not a bad day, really. Nothing flashy. But a quiet kind of progress.</p>

<hr />

<p><em>Tags: biking, site updates, obsidian, doctor who, Bible reading</em></p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="personal" /><category term="site-update" /><category term="daily-life" /><category term="obsidian" /><category term="biking" /><category term="doctor-who" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today felt like one of those quiet resets, not because anything grand happened, but because a few things finally moved forward.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Website Rant</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Website-Rant/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Website Rant" /><published>2025-04-29T01:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-29T01:45:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Website-Rant</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Website-Rant/"><![CDATA[<p>Let’s be honest, some days the world feels a little broken.</p>

<p>Not in the big dramatic "end of everything" way, but in the small stupid things: slow websites, confusing paperwork, people who block store aisles…</p>

<p>Today’s minor frustration was just trying to get this blog fully set up. Tiny tweaks turning into small problems. But you know what? I got there.</p>

<p>Sometimes you just have to rant a little, then get back to it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="Rants" /><category term="rant" /><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s be honest, some days the world feels a little broken.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Projects I’m Thinking About</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Projects-Im-Thinking-About/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Projects I’m Thinking About" /><published>2025-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Projects-Im-Thinking-About</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Projects-Im-Thinking-About/"><![CDATA[<p>Here’s a few things on my mind lately:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Expanding this blog little by little.</li>
  <li>Finding a way to organize my older writings and poems.</li>
  <li>Building some templates to aid my personal Bible study.</li>
  <li>??? Things</li>
</ul>

<p>Some of these will happen. Some might get abandoned. But that’s life, right?</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="Projects" /><category term="projects" /><category term="ideas" /><category term="planning" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s a few things on my mind lately:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why I Write (Even When I’m Not Sure)</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Why-I-Write/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I Write (Even When I’m Not Sure)" /><published>2025-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Why-I-Write</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Why-I-Write/"><![CDATA[<p>Writing has always been a strange thing for me.</p>

<p>Sometimes I write because I feel like I have something to say. Sometimes I write just because the page is there, and it’s empty, and it feels wrong to leave it blank.</p>

<p>I don’t know where this site will go. I don’t even know what exactly it will become. But I’m starting it because I want to try. To share. To build. To maybe say something that matters, even if it’s just to myself.</p>

<p>We’ll see where it leads.</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="writing" /><category term="personal" /><category term="beginning" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing has always been a strange thing for me.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Starting Somewhere</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/first-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting Somewhere" /><published>2025-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/first-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/first-blog/"><![CDATA[<p>So here we are.</p>

<p>Honestly, I don’t really know what this blog will become. I’ve started blogs before, more times than I can probably count, and somewhere along the way I either got bored, forgot about them, or just moved on. Can’t exactly say that won’t happen again, but I’m trying to do better this time around.</p>

<p>I don’t have a clear direction yet. Maybe I’ll talk about projects I’m working on, maybe share some poems or writings, maybe just rant a little when the day calls for it.</p>

<p>A little about me for anyone who stumbles across this:
I’m from Prince Edward Island, Canada, born and raised here. I have a strong Christian faith. My life changed completely back in November of 2022 when my Spouse of 16 years passed away, and then it changed again in March of 2023 when I trusted Christ for salvation. Since then, everything’s been different, not perfect, not always easy, but different in a way that matters.</p>

<p>Outside of that, I have way too many half-finished projects, a love for technology, an interest in writing, and probably too much to say when I actually sit down and start typing.</p>

<p>So here it is: the first post.</p>

<p>Let’s see where it goes.</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="journal" /><category term="Personal" /><category term="introduction" /><category term="beginning" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So here we are]]></summary></entry></feed>