<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-12T20:10:31+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Atrion’s Blog</title><subtitle>A personal public journal and blog.</subtitle><author><name>atrion</name></author><entry><title type="html">Back from Halifax onto Projects and Praise</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Back-from-Halifax-onto-Projects-and-Praise/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back from Halifax onto Projects and Praise" /><published>2025-06-11T17:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-11T17:45:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Back-from-Halifax-onto-Projects-and-Praise</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Back-from-Halifax-onto-Projects-and-Praise/"><![CDATA[<p>This past weekend was the Halifax Bible Conference, and I came away both refreshed and challenged. The focus of the Bible study and ministry was 2 Corinthians chapters 1 through 6. These chapters are rich with instruction and comfort, and the ministry was both clear and deeply rooted in Scripture. As usual, the conference delivered on all fronts; spiritually uplifting messages, good food, far too many sweets, and wonderful fellowship with believers from across the region.</p>

<p>For me, it was also a new experience. I traveled with several from my local assembly that I haven’t spent much time with before. A mix of adults and teens, a little convoy in five vehicles. Our group stayed in the home of one of their friends, a beautiful place tucked just off the water and only twenty minutes from the Gospel Hall.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>The hosts were gracious, and the full breakfasts were only matched by the warmth of the conversations. I made sure to personally thank them before leaving, and as a group, we gave them a card of thanks. I hope to see them again. New connections like this remind me how large, and yet how closely knit, the family of God truly is.</p>

<p>Shifting gears to writing updates, I recently received the final edited version of my next article for <em>RED the Island Magazine</em>. I reviewed and approved the changes, so it’s now fully set to appear in the upcoming issue next month. That said, I still need to wrap up my article for their special Christmas edition. I have most of it written, but it needs some refining, basically, I need to tone it down a little, remove some of my usual chaos, and make it resonate with a wider audience. So… maybe not as close to being done as I had hoped. Hah.</p>

<p>I also purchased a few more Island books from a local auction. I’m still figuring out storage for a previous lot that included stacks of old newspapers. Storage solutions aside, I’m happy to say the Island book collection is now fully catalogued, and I hope to make that list available here on the website soon. For anyone who shares a love of PEI history, that might be of interest.</p>

<p>Another new page is in the works: a “Projects” page, where I can store and share files from various ongoing efforts. It’ll act as a convenient hub, especially helpful when I need to send links to others or just keep my progress organized. Expect to see that appear soon in the site’s top navigation bar.</p>

<p>Two projects I’ve just wrapped up include photographing what remains of a 1910 store ledger (later repurposed as a newspaper scrapbook), and a similar scrapbook album created using a 1964 phone book. Both books are worn and fragile, but filled with historical charm. They were loaned to me by residents of Glenwood, PEI, and I’m grateful to have had the opportunity to preserve and study them.</p>

<p>This coming Sunday, I’ll be delivering a short Gospel message (around 10 to 15 minutes) at the seniors’ home. I’ve also been preparing both a Gospel message for the hall and a ministry message dealing with my own insecurities. My hope is that by speaking honestly about what I’m working through, someone else might find encouragement to keep going through their own struggles.</p>

<p>All in all, I think that gets me mostly caught up. Maybe I should be updating this blog more regularly, waiting too long makes these posts longer than they need to be.</p>

<p>And lastly, I’d be remiss if I didn’t say this: praise be to God. There are days I wouldn’t get through if it weren’t for His grace, His strength, and His unfailing presence.</p>]]></content><author><name>Marc MacArthur</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="conference" /><category term="island-books" /><category term="gospel-message" /><category term="writing" /><category term="projects" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This past weekend was the Halifax Bible Conference, and I came away both refreshed and challenged. The focus of the Bible study and ministry was 2 Corinthians chapters 1 through 6. These chapters are rich with instruction and comfort, and the ministry was both clear and deeply rooted in Scripture. As usual, the conference delivered on all fronts; spiritually uplifting messages, good food, far too many sweets, and wonderful fellowship with believers from across the region. For me, it was also a new experience. I traveled with several from my local assembly that I haven’t spent much time with before. A mix of adults and teens, a little convoy in five vehicles. Our group stayed in the home of one of their friends, a beautiful place tucked just off the water and only twenty minutes from the Gospel Hall.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Zoom Messages Missed Opportunities and the Week Ahead</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Zoom-Messages-Missed-Opportunities-and-the-Week-Ahead/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Zoom Messages Missed Opportunities and the Week Ahead" /><published>2025-06-01T23:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-01T23:45:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Zoom-Messages-Missed-Opportunities-and-the-Week-Ahead</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Zoom-Messages-Missed-Opportunities-and-the-Week-Ahead/"><![CDATA[<p>Saturday morning I had the opportunity to share the Gospel during a Zoom meeting for the Philippines. The whole session ran about 30 minutes, with my portion taking around 15. I tried something new this time: instead of just a single camera feed, I used a dual-window setup. My video was in the lower-left corner, and the main screen displayed Bible verses in both English and Tagalog. I used <strong>FreeShow</strong> for the Scripture display and <strong>OBS</strong> to tie everything together.</p>

<p>I <em>think</em> it went well, but I’m never the best judge of my own speaking. I tend to second guess how it landed. Sometimes I wonder if people say the message was good just to keep from discouraging me.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>Now I’m working on a ministry message for later this month, our usual <strong>second Thursday</strong> ministry night. I’ve also started laying the groundwork for a written devotional series based on the <strong>churches in Revelation</strong>. That project is still in the research phase, but it’s taking shape. In addition, I’m preparing a spoken devotional for <strong>Orangewood Gospel Hall’s Saturday Zoom broadcast</strong>.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><em>Take all our troubles to God in prayer.</em><br />
But I often wonder what His response is, or if I even hear it right.<br />
I still struggle with myself; with anxiety, hesitation, and self-doubt.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>There are moments when I want to stand up during a meeting and pray, or share verses or ministry, but I hold back. I fight myself - mentally and emotionally - and more often than not, I end up sitting in silence.</p>

<p>That said, I <em>did</em> follow through on the Zoom Gospel this past Saturday. And I’m scheduled for a short Gospel message at <strong>The Willows</strong> the Sunday after next.</p>

<p>I’ve learned that once I commit to speaking, I follow through, even if I don’t always feel like the message is great. But trying to apply that same mindset in regular meetings doesn’t always work.</p>

<p>Some days I wonder if my faith is lacking, not because I don’t believe, but because <strong>I get in the way of myself</strong>.</p>

<p>If you’ve read this far, you’ve probably gathered that my brain is a strange place to be. Hah!</p>

<hr />

<p>Another Sunday has come and gone without me rising to speak. The meeting was fairly full, with a visiting guest in as well, so things moved quickly from one speaker to the next. That’s my <em>excuse</em>, anyway. Deep down I know it’s just that, an excuse. And it frustrates me. Then I get frustrated about being frustrated. A cycle.</p>

<hr />

<p>We had a <strong>free yard sale</strong> at the hall on Saturday. I wasn’t able to attend, but I did contribute a few books and designed the flyer and online ad. Unfortunately, it also led to an issue Sunday morning, I was running late and didn’t realize the <strong>main microphone had been unplugged</strong> for the yard sale. I didn’t notice it wasn’t reconnected. So the <strong>Sunday morning audio recording</strong> ended up being captured only by the backup mic at the back of the room. That mic is old, meant mostly for enhancing hymn vocals. The result: muddy, distant audio. I managed to salvage part of the message, but not all. Disappointing, but a lesson learned.</p>

<hr />

<p>This upcoming weekend I’ll be traveling to the <strong>Halifax Bible Study Conference</strong>. I’ll be going with a few people I haven’t traveled with before, so that’ll be a new experience. I’m still not sure if we leave Friday or Saturday, but I’ll have the full details soon. It may be socially exhausting, but I truly think (and pray) it will be worth it. Even just for the time in the Word and the ministry itself.</p>

<p>More updates to come - Lord willing.</p>]]></content><author><name>Marc MacArthur</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="zoom-message" /><category term="gospel" /><category term="ministry-prep" /><category term="personal-struggle" /><category term="conference" /><category term="devotional-writing" /><category term="recording-issues" /><category term="travel" /><category term="halifax-conference" /><category term="anxiety" /><category term="prayer" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Saturday morning I had the opportunity to share the Gospel during a Zoom meeting for the Philippines. The whole session ran about 30 minutes, with my portion taking around 15. I tried something new this time: instead of just a single camera feed, I used a dual-window setup. My video was in the lower-left corner, and the main screen displayed Bible verses in both English and Tagalog. I used FreeShow for the Scripture display and OBS to tie everything together. I think it went well, but I’m never the best judge of my own speaking. I tend to second guess how it landed. Sometimes I wonder if people say the message was good just to keep from discouraging me.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Preparing the Message Cataloging the Library</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Preparing-the-Message-Cataloging-the-Library/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Preparing the Message Cataloging the Library" /><published>2025-05-22T20:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-22T20:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Preparing-the-Message-Cataloging-the-Library</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Preparing-the-Message-Cataloging-the-Library/"><![CDATA[<p>Lately I’ve been working on my Gospel message for the upcoming Zoom meeting with the Philippines, scheduled for May 31st. It’s been on my mind more than usual. I tend to second-guess my messages, not because I don’t believe them, but because I often lack a bit of confidence in my delivery.</p>

<p>My friend Timmy, who passed away earlier this year, used to review all of my messages before I shared them. He was a trusted sounding board, and I leaned on his input more than I realized. Knowing someone else had read through what I had prepared always gave me some peace of mind, that I was on the right track. I miss that encouragement.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>I’m also not the most comfortable speaker. Unlike many who go up with a few bullet points or rely on a flow of spontaneous thought, I write everything out, word for word. That’s how I make sense of the message. The clarity doesn’t usually come when I stand up to speak; it comes when pen hits paper (or more often, fingers hit the keyboard). I do sometimes veer from the script in the moment, but having every word written means that when my mind blanks, I’m not stuck.</p>

<p>Outside of message prep, I’ve been slowly cataloging my personal book collection, starting with the PEI books. It’s a larger task than I expected. Only about half of them scanned properly, and of those, I’ve had to manually add cover images for nearly half again. And of course, the other half didn’t scan at all. So now I’m plugging them in manually one by one. It’s slow work, but it’s necessary. I’ve already bought duplicates more than once simply because I forgot what I had.</p>

<p>Tonight is prayer and Bible study at the O’Leary Gospel Hall. We’re starting at 1 Peter 1:18, likely wrapping up the rest of the chapter. I’d like to say I’m ready, but more often than not, I feel like I’m more prepared than I actually am. Still, being among the believers, digging into the Word, it always turns out to be worthwhile, whether I speak up or not.</p>

<p>We press on.</p>]]></content><author><name>Marc MacArthur</name></author><category term="Reflections" /><category term="gospel" /><category term="bible study" /><category term="books" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Lately I’ve been working on my Gospel message for the upcoming Zoom meeting with the Philippines, scheduled for May 31st. It’s been on my mind more than usual. I tend to second-guess my messages, not because I don’t believe them, but because I often lack a bit of confidence in my delivery. My friend Timmy, who passed away earlier this year, used to review all of my messages before I shared them. He was a trusted sounding board, and I leaned on his input more than I realized. Knowing someone else had read through what I had prepared always gave me some peace of mind, that I was on the right track. I miss that encouragement.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Post-Conference Reflections and Birthday Moments</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Post-Conference-Reflections-and-Birthday-Moments/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post-Conference Reflections and Birthday Moments" /><published>2025-05-20T02:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-20T02:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Post-Conference-Reflections-and-Birthday-Moments</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Post-Conference-Reflections-and-Birthday-Moments/"><![CDATA[<p>So, it’s been a bit since the last post.</p>

<p>The Island Gospel Conference just wrapped up this past weekend. It was held at Bluefield School, and as always, it was a blessing. Solid ministry, a clear and faithful gospel message, more good food than any of us needed, sugary desserts that tested everyone’s resolve, and most of all, amazing fellowship with other believers.</p>

<p>I had some deep, meaningful conversations with a few preachers whose words and lives have been a great inspiration to me. Moments like that stick with you.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>There was a particularly encouraging moment when someone who hadn’t seen me since before I started my diet pointed out how much weight I’d lost. I’m not sure I always see it myself, but it meant a lot to hear it from someone who remembered what I looked like before. Here’s hoping the next six months bring the same kind of progress.</p>

<p>Today was the birthday of a friend, and the wife of another friend, part of the MacKenzie family, who truly treat me like one of their own. They’re always kind, warm, and welcoming, and I’ve never left their home without a smile. We shared a big meal, had cake for her, and surprisingly another cake for me, since my birthday is tomorrow. I got to spend time with the whole family, chatted with the adults, and read a few books to the kids. Honestly, it was one of those evenings that reminds you what real community looks like.</p>

<p>The challenge now is to carry the weight of the ministry shared at the conference into daily life. It’s easy to let the “conference high” fade once everything returns to normal. I’ve started relistening to some of the messages and taking notes. Truthfully, I really need to learn to take notes during the meetings themselves, but there’s something about hearing it again that helps it finally land.</p>

<p>A friend of mine has his girlfriend visiting, but her trip is nearing its end, she leaves mid-day Wednesday. I know it’s going to be tough for him once she’s gone. Sometimes the hardest part of something good is saying goodbye to it, even if it is only for a time.</p>

<p>And as for this blog, I can’t let it go the way of so many past attempts. I’m not aiming to post daily, but I need to commit to at least a weekly update. It helps keep the momentum going and keeps me grounded.</p>

<p>If everything worked like I hoped, there should be a few images from the conference just below. (Still figuring this part out.)</p>

<p>Until next time.</p>

<div class="gallery">
  <a href="/blog/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250517_161032377.jpg" target="_blank">
    <img src="/blog/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250517_161032377.jpg" alt="2025 PEI Conference" />
  </a>
  <a href="/blog/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250517_162737697.jpg" target="_blank">
    <img src="/blog/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250517_162737697.jpg" alt="2025 PEI Conference" />
  </a>
  <a href="/blog/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250517_202247783.MP.jpg" target="_blank">
    <img src="/blog/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250517_202247783.MP.jpg" alt="2025 PEI Conference" />
  </a>
    <a href="/blog/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250518_184757887.jpg" target="_blank">
    <img src="/blog/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250518_184757887.jpg" alt="2025 PEI Conference" />
  </a>
  <a href="/blog/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250518_184759911.jpg" target="_blank">
    <img src="/blog/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250518_184759911.jpg" alt="2025 PEI Conference" />
  </a>
  <a href="/blog/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250519_002509366.jpg" target="_blank">
    <img src="/blog/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250519_002509366.jpg" alt="2025 PEI Conference" />
  </a>
    <a href="/blog/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250519_002510994.jpg" target="_blank">
    <img src="/blog/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250519_002510994.jpg" alt="2025 PEI Conference" />
  </a>
  <a href="/blog/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250519_002512146.jpg" target="_blank">
    <img src="/blog/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250517_161032377.jpg" alt="2025 PEI Conference" />
  </a>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Marc MacArthur</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="conference" /><category term="gospel" /><category term="ministry" /><category term="fellowship" /><category term="birthday" /><category term="reflection" /><category term="weight-loss" /><category term="friends" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, it’s been a bit since the last post. The Island Gospel Conference just wrapped up this past weekend. It was held at Bluefield School, and as always, it was a blessing. Solid ministry, a clear and faithful gospel message, more good food than any of us needed, sugary desserts that tested everyone’s resolve, and most of all, amazing fellowship with other believers. I had some deep, meaningful conversations with a few preachers whose words and lives have been a great inspiration to me. Moments like that stick with you.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quiet Site Work and Quiet Thoughts</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Quiet-Site-Work-and-Quiet-Thoughts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quiet Site Work and Quiet Thoughts" /><published>2025-05-12T21:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-12T21:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Quiet-Site-Work-and-Quiet-Thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Quiet-Site-Work-and-Quiet-Thoughts/"><![CDATA[<p>Just a short note for now, nothing major to update, but still a few small things in progress behind the scenes.</p>

<p>I’ve been working on formatting some <strong>new design options</strong> for this site. Mostly layout tweaks and trying out different ways to display things better, especially the poetry section. Speaking of which, I plan to <strong>upload a few more poems</strong> this week, some older, some recent. I’m trying to get better at sharing them, rather than letting them sit forgotten in folders.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>Also starting to wonder: <strong>has anyone actually been reading any of this?</strong> Not that I mind if not, this space still helps me get my thoughts in order. But part of me wonders if a <strong>commenting feature</strong> might be something to look into. Maybe there’s a simple way to implement one without making things messy or difficult to maintain. We’ll see.</p>

<p>Anyway, just keeping things moving quietly. Updates will be small and steady. As always, thanks if you’re reading, even silently.</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="updates" /><category term="poetry" /><category term="site changes" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just a short note for now, nothing major to update, but still a few small things in progress behind the scenes. I’ve been working on formatting some new design options for this site. Mostly layout tweaks and trying out different ways to display things better, especially the poetry section. Speaking of which, I plan to upload a few more poems this week, some older, some recent. I’m trying to get better at sharing them, rather than letting them sit forgotten in folders.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Bit of This, A Bit of That</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/A-Bit-of-This-A-Bit-of-That/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Bit of This, A Bit of That" /><published>2025-05-10T20:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-10T20:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/A-Bit-of-This-A-Bit-of-That</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/A-Bit-of-This-A-Bit-of-That/"><![CDATA[<p>Not a whole lot to report today, but I’ll put a few things down while I’ve got the time and clarity.</p>

<p><strong>Thursday night’s meeting</strong> was encouraging, though I didn’t get up to speak this time. The prayer portion ran longer than usual, which is a good problem to have. After that, another Brother stood up and shared a message that really uplifted the assembly. So while I stayed quiet, I don’t see that as a loss, the message that was needed got spoken, and I was glad to hear it.</p>

<p><strong>Friday</strong> was the usual grocery day: expensive, dull, and necessary. Not much else to say there.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>I’ve spent a good chunk of the week <strong>reformatting and organizing my notes in Obsidian</strong>, moving over transcripts, personal writings, poetry, and more. The structure is starting to make sense now.</p>

<p>Two writing projects hit milestones this week. I finished off a devotional series on <strong>“The Christian Armour”</strong> and completed <strong>Part One</strong> of an article titled <strong>“The Gift of Singleness.”</strong> So far, the devotional pieces have been shared within my assembly and with a trusted friend who’s also a preacher. I’ve also passed the article along to him and hope to get some honest feedback soon.</p>

<p>Today was a bit more lively. The siblings came over, and we had a combined family get-together ( part late Easter, part Mother’s Day, part Mom’s birthday, part my own birthday). Just a simple afternoon with pizza, cake, and the nephews. Nothing fancy, but good to have everyone under the same roof for a while.</p>

<p><strong>Tomorrow morning is our usual Gospel meeting for the Philippines via Zoom.</strong> My turn to speak is coming up at the end of the month (May 31st), so I’ll need to start praying and preparing for that as well.</p>

<p>My sister also brought up some books and magazines I picked up in a recent local auction. What I thought was just a single bound volume of 1920s newspapers has turned out to be one full book <em>plus</em> several bags of partial bindings. That’s going to take some sorting, and I’m not sure where I’m putting it all yet.</p>

<p>Which ties into another ongoing task: <strong>figuring out a way to properly catalogue my Island book collection.</strong> A lot of these books don’t have ISBNs, either due to age or obscurity, and many aren’t listed in any known databases. I might have to do this manually, which is a daunting prospect, but I want to make sure they’re preserved and documented.</p>

<p>Tonight there’s a <strong>devotional message on Zoom</strong>, hosted by <strong>Orangewood Gospel Hall in the USA</strong>. Then it’s off to bed and preparing my heart and mind for the <strong>Worship and Breaking of Bread meeting</strong> tomorrow morning.</p>

<p>That’s it for now. Just a mix of small updates and quiet work.</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="personal" /><category term="updates" /><category term="obsidian" /><category term="family" /><category term="writing" /><category term="gospel" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not a whole lot to report today, but I’ll put a few things down while I’ve got the time and clarity. Thursday night’s meeting was encouraging, though I didn’t get up to speak this time. The prayer portion ran longer than usual, which is a good problem to have. After that, another Brother stood up and shared a message that really uplifted the assembly. So while I stayed quiet, I don’t see that as a loss, the message that was needed got spoken, and I was glad to hear it. Friday was the usual grocery day: expensive, dull, and necessary. Not much else to say there.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Six Months Down</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Six-Months-Down/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Six Months Down" /><published>2025-05-08T17:18:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-08T17:18:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Six-Months-Down</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Six-Months-Down/"><![CDATA[<p>Today marks <strong>six months</strong> since I started changing my diet.</p>

<p>It hasn’t always been easy, but it’s been worth it. I’m down another <strong>3.9 lbs this week</strong>, bringing the total weight lost so far to <strong>77.6 lbs</strong>. It still surprises me seeing the number go down like that, but I’m learning not to question good progress. Just keep at it, day by day.</p>

<!--more-->
<hr />

<p>On the productivity side, I’m finally getting the hang of <strong>Obsidian</strong>,  at least the basics. I’ve started moving my <strong>Bible study notes</strong> into the vault, trying to organize them in a way that makes sense long-term. Same goes for my scattered thoughts, plans, and project outlines.</p>

<p>For writing, I’m still using <strong>Google Docs</strong> when it comes to longer articles. It’s just easier for layout and editing, especially when I’m on the go. But I’m thinking of switching from <strong>Google Keep</strong> to the <strong>Android version of Obsidian</strong> for note-taking. We’ll see how that works in practice.</p>

<hr />

<p>Tonight is the Prayer Meeting and Ministry message at <strong>O’Leary Gospel Hall</strong>. I’ve had some thoughts rattling around, maybe even the bones of a message, but I haven’t managed to piece it all together. I’m not even sure if I’ll stand up and speak at all. The hesitation is frustrating, but I’m learning not to push myself too hard.</p>

<p>Just thought I’d check in and record it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="weight loss" /><category term="personal" /><category term="obsidian" /><category term="bible study" /><category term="gospel hall" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks six months since I started changing my diet. It hasn’t always been easy, but it’s been worth it. I’m down another 3.9 lbs this week, bringing the total weight lost so far to 77.6 lbs. It still surprises me seeing the number go down like that, but I’m learning not to question good progress. Just keep at it, day by day.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Running on Fumes and Thoughts</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Running-on-Fumes-and-Thoughts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running on Fumes and Thoughts" /><published>2025-05-05T14:50:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-05T14:50:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Running-on-Fumes-and-Thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Running-on-Fumes-and-Thoughts/"><![CDATA[<p>Running into Sunday with absolutely zero sleep is a special kind of disorientation. I’m not sure how I managed to function, but I did. And somehow, the Lord’s Day worship and breaking of bread was good, peaceful, weighty, needed.</p>

<p>I had something on my heart to share during the meeting, but once again, I kept quiet. I don’t know why I freeze up when it matters. It’s frustrating, because it felt like something I was meant to say. And I didn’t.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>There was a baptism at the hall after. That always puts things in perspective. New beginnings, public faith, the beauty of submission. After everyone left, I stayed behind and spent most of the afternoon alone at the hall. Tried to nap a bit, didn’t happen. Ended up making a coffee and settling in reading my Bible for a while.</p>

<p>Later, while editing the audio from the day’s messages, I managed to put the wrong last name on one of the speakers. As soon as people noticed, I felt embarrassed and honestly, kind of foolish.</p>

<p>This week’s writing goal is to wrap up an article I’ve been drafting in hopes of submitting it somewhere. I also unearthed some very old poetry; cringy stuff from years back; that I’m thinking of retyping and archiving. Maybe I’ll even post a few, if I can get over the secondhand embarrassment. There’s also a Christian-centered article I keep setting aside. Feels like it deserves more attention than I’ve been giving it, even if I don’t know who’s actually reading any of this besides me.</p>

<p>Might look into some local outlets for submitting writing, too. I don’t expect much, but I want to start trying more. If nothing else, it helps me keep moving.</p>

<p>The diet’s still on track, even if the weight loss has slowed a bit. Still, slow progress is better than none, and definitely better than the alternative.</p>

<p>That ministry message from Sunday morning has stuck with me. Still chewing on it. No flashy takeaway yet, just the quiet nudge that there’s something there I need to sit with.</p>

<p>Anyway, that’s where I’m at. Tired. Reflective. Trying.</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="journal" /><category term="journal" /><category term="worship" /><category term="writing" /><category term="poetry" /><category term="diet" /><category term="reflection" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Running into Sunday with absolutely zero sleep is a special kind of disorientation. I’m not sure how I managed to function, but I did. And somehow, the Lord’s Day worship and breaking of bread was good, peaceful, weighty, needed. I had something on my heart to share during the meeting, but once again, I kept quiet. I don’t know why I freeze up when it matters. It’s frustrating, because it felt like something I was meant to say. And I didn’t.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bits and Pieces and Bread</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Bits-and-Pieces-and-Bread/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bits and Pieces and Bread" /><published>2025-05-03T17:35:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-03T17:35:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Bits-and-Pieces-and-Bread</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Bits-and-Pieces-and-Bread/"><![CDATA[<p>It’s one of those days where everything I own seems to be in a different pile. Notes tucked into old folders, ideas scribbled on scraps I barely remember writing, photos scanned but never sorted, there’s just a little bit of everything and a whole lot of nowhere to put it.</p>

<p>I’ve been chipping away at deciding what’s worth keeping, what needs to be worked on, and what’s finally ready for the trash. You’d think after all this time I’d be better at staying organized, but then again, maybe that’s part of the charm. Or at least, that’s what I tell myself.</p>

<!--more-->

<p>Somehow in the middle of all this, I’ve found myself juggling two writing projects and a couple of research tangents that feel like they’ve spiraled into full dissertations. If only this scattered brain could pay the bills, right? Hah.</p>

<p>The Island Gospel Conference is coming up in a couple weeks, weekend of the 17th. I tried going to a ministry meeting with a friend last night. Turns out it wasn’t on. We only figured that out after we got there. Made the best of it though, met up with someone else instead, grabbed some food, and had some genuinely good conversations. Sometimes plans falling through lead to better ones.</p>

<p>I’ve also been thinking about journaling lately. It’s something I’ve never been great at. I’ll go through spurts and stops, but I’m always glad when I have a record to look back on later. Not because I think anything I’ve done is all that remarkable, but just because it’s good to remember. These posts are kind of like a public journal. I’ve kept private ones, too. Some are still around. Some probably got tossed in one of those cleaning frenzies. That’s okay.</p>

<p>Anyway, time to get back to sorting and writing. Maybe I’ll actually finish something tonight, but first, Bible reading and getting myself ready for tomorrow’s worship and breaking of bread. Everything else can wait a bit.</p>

<p>Until next time.</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="journal" /><category term="journal" /><category term="projects" /><category term="photos" /><category term="writing" /><category term="gospel" /><category term="Bible" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s one of those days where everything I own seems to be in a different pile. Notes tucked into old folders, ideas scribbled on scraps I barely remember writing, photos scanned but never sorted, there’s just a little bit of everything and a whole lot of nowhere to put it. I’ve been chipping away at deciding what’s worth keeping, what needs to be worked on, and what’s finally ready for the trash. You’d think after all this time I’d be better at staying organized, but then again, maybe that’s part of the charm. Or at least, that’s what I tell myself.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Getting Back Into Things</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Getting-Back-Into-Things/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting Back Into Things" /><published>2025-04-30T02:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-30T02:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Getting-Back-Into-Things</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Getting-Back-Into-Things/"><![CDATA[<p>Today felt like one of those quiet resets, not because anything grand happened, but because a few things finally moved forward.</p>

<p>For one, I got back on a bike again. It’s been years. My legs remembered how (mostly), but that seat has no mercy. Felt like I pedaled for five minutes and had earned an ice pack and a nap. But it’s a start. The plan isn’t distance or speed right now it’s <em>consistency</em>.</p>

<p>I also took some time to clean up this site, just a bunch of small updates here and there. Little style tweaks, layout fixes, improved tagging. I want this to be something I can build on slowly, not something that gets away from me like blogs in the past.</p>

<p>That goes for my Obsidian vault too. It got overgrown, bloated with folders and tags and items I wasn’t really using. Today was the start of a trim-back. Reorganizing and deleting. I’m trying to return it to a place where I can write and reflect, not just manage a maze.</p>

<p>To balance things out, I started a rewatch of <em>Doctor Who,</em> back to the Ninth Doctor and all the leather-jacket nostalgia. There’s something nice about returning to stories that once felt like home.</p>

<p>And of course, I kept up with my Bible reading schedule. Today’s portion was:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Leviticus 23</strong> About the feasts of the Lord, which were always more than calendar events, they were reminders of who He is.</li>
  <li><strong>Psalm 80</strong> A cry for restoration, written from the ache of distance and the hope of mercy.</li>
  <li><strong>Matthew 21</strong> The entry into Jerusalem and the clearing of the temple; a shift in tone and pace as the cross drew closer.</li>
</ul>

<p>Not a bad day, really. Nothing flashy. But a quiet kind of progress.</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="personal" /><category term="site-update" /><category term="daily-life" /><category term="obsidian" /><category term="biking" /><category term="doctor-who" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today felt like one of those quiet resets, not because anything grand happened, but because a few things finally moved forward. For one, I got back on a bike again. It’s been years. My legs remembered how (mostly), but that seat has no mercy. Felt like I pedaled for five minutes and had earned an ice pack and a nap. But it’s a start. The plan isn’t distance or speed right now it’s consistency. I also took some time to clean up this site, just a bunch of small updates here and there. Little style tweaks, layout fixes, improved tagging. I want this to be something I can build on slowly, not something that gets away from me like blogs in the past. That goes for my Obsidian vault too. It got overgrown, bloated with folders and tags and items I wasn’t really using. Today was the start of a trim-back. Reorganizing and deleting. I’m trying to return it to a place where I can write and reflect, not just manage a maze. To balance things out, I started a rewatch of Doctor Who, back to the Ninth Doctor and all the leather-jacket nostalgia. There’s something nice about returning to stories that once felt like home. And of course, I kept up with my Bible reading schedule. Today’s portion was: Leviticus 23 About the feasts of the Lord, which were always more than calendar events, they were reminders of who He is. Psalm 80 A cry for restoration, written from the ache of distance and the hope of mercy. Matthew 21 The entry into Jerusalem and the clearing of the temple; a shift in tone and pace as the cross drew closer. Not a bad day, really. Nothing flashy. But a quiet kind of progress.]]></summary></entry></feed>