<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-05-20T04:29:05+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Atrion’s Blog</title><subtitle>A personal public journal and blog.</subtitle><author><name>atrion</name></author><entry><title type="html">Post-Conference Reflections and Birthday Moments</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Post-Conference-Reflections-and-Birthday-Moments/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Post-Conference Reflections and Birthday Moments" /><published>2025-05-20T02:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-20T02:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Post-Conference-Reflections-and-Birthday-Moments</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Post-Conference-Reflections-and-Birthday-Moments/"><![CDATA[<p>So, it’s been a bit since the last post.</p>

<p>The Island Gospel Conference just wrapped up this past weekend. It was held at Bluefield School, and as always, it was a blessing. Solid ministry, a clear and faithful gospel message, more good food than any of us needed, sugary desserts that tested everyone’s resolve, and most of all, amazing fellowship with other believers.</p>

<p>I had some deep, meaningful conversations with a few preachers whose words and lives have been a great inspiration to me. Moments like that stick with you.</p>

<p>There was a particularly encouraging moment when someone who hadn’t seen me since before I started my diet pointed out how much weight I’d lost. I’m not sure I always see it myself, but it meant a lot to hear it from someone who remembered what I looked like before. Here’s hoping the next six months bring the same kind of progress.</p>

<p>Today was the birthday of a friend, and the wife of another friend, part of the MacKenzie family, who truly treat me like one of their own. They’re always kind, warm, and welcoming, and I’ve never left their home without a smile. We shared a big meal, had cake for her, and surprisingly another cake for me, since my birthday is tomorrow. I got to spend time with the whole family, chatted with the adults, and read a few books to the kids. Honestly, it was one of those evenings that reminds you what real community looks like.</p>

<p>The challenge now is to carry the weight of the ministry shared at the conference into daily life. It’s easy to let the “conference high” fade once everything returns to normal. I’ve started relistening to some of the messages and taking notes. Truthfully, I really need to learn to take notes during the meetings themselves, but there’s something about hearing it again that helps it finally land.</p>

<p>A friend of mine has his girlfriend visiting, but her trip is nearing its end, she leaves mid-day Wednesday. I know it’s going to be tough for him once she’s gone. Sometimes the hardest part of something good is saying goodbye to it, even if it is only for a time.</p>

<p>And as for this blog, I can’t let it go the way of so many past attempts. I’m not aiming to post daily, but I need to commit to at least a weekly update. It helps keep the momentum going and keeps me grounded.</p>

<p>If everything worked like I hoped, there should be a few images from the conference just below. (Still figuring this part out.)</p>

<p>Until next time.</p>

<div class="gallery">
  <a href="/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250517_161032377.jpg" target="_blank">
    <img src="/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250517_161032377.jpg" alt="2025 PEI Conference" />
  </a>
  <a href="/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250517_162737697.jpg" target="_blank">
    <img src="/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250517_162737697.jpg" alt="2025 PEI Conference" />
  </a>
  <a href="/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250517_202247783.MP.jpg" target="_blank">
    <img src="/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250517_202247783.MP.jpg" alt="2025 PEI Conference" />
  </a>
    <a href="/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250518_184757887.jpg" target="_blank">
    <img src="/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250518_184757887.jpg" alt="2025 PEI Conference" />
  </a>
  <a href="/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250518_184759911.jpg" target="_blank">
    <img src="/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250518_184759911.jpg" alt="2025 PEI Conference" />
  </a>
  <a href="/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250519_002509366.jpg" target="_blank">
    <img src="/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250519_002509366.jpg" alt="2025 PEI Conference" />
  </a>
    <a href="/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250519_002510994.jpg" target="_blank">
    <img src="/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250519_002510994.jpg" alt="2025 PEI Conference" />
  </a>
  <a href="/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250519_002512146.jpg" target="_blank">
    <img src="/blog/assets/images/2025-05-19/PXL_20250517_161032377.jpg" alt="2025 PEI Conference" />
  </a>
</div>]]></content><author><name>Marc MacArthur</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="conference" /><category term="gospel" /><category term="ministry" /><category term="fellowship" /><category term="birthday" /><category term="reflection" /><category term="weight-loss" /><category term="friends" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[So, it’s been a bit since the last post.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quiet Site Work and Quiet Thoughts</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Quiet-Site-Work-and-Quiet-Thoughts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quiet Site Work and Quiet Thoughts" /><published>2025-05-12T21:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-12T21:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Quiet-Site-Work-and-Quiet-Thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Quiet-Site-Work-and-Quiet-Thoughts/"><![CDATA[<p>Just a short note for now, nothing major to update, but still a few small things in progress behind the scenes.</p>

<p>I’ve been working on formatting some <strong>new design options</strong> for this site. Mostly layout tweaks and trying out different ways to display things better, especially the poetry section. Speaking of which, I plan to <strong>upload a few more poems</strong> this week, some older, some recent. I’m trying to get better at sharing them, rather than letting them sit forgotten in folders.</p>

<p>Also starting to wonder: <strong>has anyone actually been reading any of this?</strong> Not that I mind if not, this space still helps me get my thoughts in order. But part of me wonders if a <strong>commenting feature</strong> might be something to look into. Maybe there’s a simple way to implement one without making things messy or difficult to maintain. We’ll see.</p>

<p>Anyway, just keeping things moving quietly. Updates will be small and steady. As always, thanks if you’re reading, even silently.</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="updates" /><category term="poetry" /><category term="site changes" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Just a short note for now, nothing major to update, but still a few small things in progress behind the scenes.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Bit of This, A Bit of That</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/A-Bit-of-This-A-Bit-of-That/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Bit of This, A Bit of That" /><published>2025-05-10T20:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-10T20:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/A-Bit-of-This-A-Bit-of-That</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/A-Bit-of-This-A-Bit-of-That/"><![CDATA[<p>Not a whole lot to report today, but I’ll put a few things down while I’ve got the time and clarity.</p>

<p><strong>Thursday night’s meeting</strong> was encouraging, though I didn’t get up to speak this time. The prayer portion ran longer than usual, which is a good problem to have. After that, another Brother stood up and shared a message that really uplifted the assembly. So while I stayed quiet, I don’t see that as a loss, the message that was needed got spoken, and I was glad to hear it.</p>

<p><strong>Friday</strong> was the usual grocery day: expensive, dull, and necessary. Not much else to say there.</p>

<p>I’ve spent a good chunk of the week <strong>reformatting and organizing my notes in Obsidian</strong>, moving over transcripts, personal writings, poetry, and more. The structure is starting to make sense now.</p>

<p>Two writing projects hit milestones this week. I finished off a devotional series on <strong>“The Christian Armour”</strong> and completed <strong>Part One</strong> of an article titled <strong>“The Gift of Singleness.”</strong> So far, the devotional pieces have been shared within my assembly and with a trusted friend who’s also a preacher. I’ve also passed the article along to him and hope to get some honest feedback soon.</p>

<p>Today was a bit more lively. The siblings came over, and we had a combined family get-together ( part late Easter, part Mother’s Day, part Mom’s birthday, part my own birthday). Just a simple afternoon with pizza, cake, and the nephews. Nothing fancy, but good to have everyone under the same roof for a while.</p>

<p><strong>Tomorrow morning is our usual Gospel meeting for the Philippines via Zoom.</strong> My turn to speak is coming up at the end of the month (May 31st), so I’ll need to start praying and preparing for that as well.</p>

<p>My sister also brought up some books and magazines I picked up in a recent local auction. What I thought was just a single bound volume of 1920s newspapers has turned out to be one full book <em>plus</em> several bags of partial bindings. That’s going to take some sorting, and I’m not sure where I’m putting it all yet.</p>

<p>Which ties into another ongoing task: <strong>figuring out a way to properly catalogue my Island book collection.</strong> A lot of these books don’t have ISBNs, either due to age or obscurity, and many aren’t listed in any known databases. I might have to do this manually, which is a daunting prospect, but I want to make sure they’re preserved and documented.</p>

<p>Tonight there’s a <strong>devotional message on Zoom</strong>, hosted by <strong>Orangewood Gospel Hall in the USA</strong>. Then it’s off to bed and preparing my heart and mind for the <strong>Worship and Breaking of Bread meeting</strong> tomorrow morning.</p>

<p>That’s it for now. Just a mix of small updates and quiet work.</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="personal" /><category term="updates" /><category term="obsidian" /><category term="family" /><category term="writing" /><category term="gospel" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Not a whole lot to report today, but I’ll put a few things down while I’ve got the time and clarity.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Six Months Down</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Six-Months-Down/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Six Months Down" /><published>2025-05-08T17:18:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-08T17:18:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Six-Months-Down</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Six-Months-Down/"><![CDATA[<p>Today marks <strong>six months</strong> since I started changing my diet.</p>

<p>It hasn’t always been easy, but it’s been worth it. I’m down another <strong>3.9 lbs this week</strong>, bringing the total weight lost so far to <strong>77.6 lbs</strong>. It still surprises me seeing the number go down like that, but I’m learning not to question good progress. Just keep at it, day by day.</p>

<hr />

<p>On the productivity side, I’m finally getting the hang of <strong>Obsidian</strong>,  at least the basics. I’ve started moving my <strong>Bible study notes</strong> into the vault, trying to organize them in a way that makes sense long-term. Same goes for my scattered thoughts, plans, and project outlines.</p>

<p>For writing, I’m still using <strong>Google Docs</strong> when it comes to longer articles. It’s just easier for layout and editing, especially when I’m on the go. But I’m thinking of switching from <strong>Google Keep</strong> to the <strong>Android version of Obsidian</strong> for note-taking. We’ll see how that works in practice.</p>

<hr />

<p>Tonight is the Prayer Meeting and Ministry message at <strong>O’Leary Gospel Hall</strong>. I’ve had some thoughts rattling around, maybe even the bones of a message, but I haven’t managed to piece it all together. I’m not even sure if I’ll stand up and speak at all. The hesitation is frustrating, but I’m learning not to push myself too hard.</p>

<p>Just thought I’d check in and record it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="personal" /><category term="weight loss" /><category term="personal" /><category term="obsidian" /><category term="bible study" /><category term="gospel hall" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today marks six months since I started changing my diet.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Running on Fumes and Thoughts</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Running-on-Fumes-and-Thoughts/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running on Fumes and Thoughts" /><published>2025-05-05T14:50:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-05T14:50:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Running-on-Fumes-and-Thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Running-on-Fumes-and-Thoughts/"><![CDATA[<p>Running into Sunday with absolutely zero sleep is a special kind of disorientation. I’m not sure how I managed to function, but I did. And somehow, the Lord’s Day worship and breaking of bread was good, peaceful, weighty, needed.</p>

<p>I had something on my heart to share during the meeting, but once again, I kept quiet. I don’t know why I freeze up when it matters. It’s frustrating, because it felt like something I was meant to say. And I didn’t.</p>

<p>There was a baptism at the hall after. That always puts things in perspective. New beginnings, public faith, the beauty of submission. After everyone left, I stayed behind and spent most of the afternoon alone at the hall. Tried to nap a bit, didn’t happen. Ended up making a coffee and settling in reading my Bible for a while.</p>

<p>Later, while editing the audio from the day’s messages, I managed to put the wrong last name on one of the speakers. As soon as people noticed, I felt embarrassed and honestly, kind of foolish.</p>

<p>This week’s writing goal is to wrap up an article I’ve been drafting in hopes of submitting it somewhere. I also unearthed some very old poetry; cringy stuff from years back; that I’m thinking of retyping and archiving. Maybe I’ll even post a few, if I can get over the secondhand embarrassment. There’s also a Christian-centered article I keep setting aside. Feels like it deserves more attention than I’ve been giving it, even if I don’t know who’s actually reading any of this besides me.</p>

<p>Might look into some local outlets for submitting writing, too. I don’t expect much, but I want to start trying more. If nothing else, it helps me keep moving.</p>

<p>The diet’s still on track, even if the weight loss has slowed a bit. Still, slow progress is better than none, and definitely better than the alternative.</p>

<p>That ministry message from Sunday morning has stuck with me. Still chewing on it. No flashy takeaway yet, just the quiet nudge that there’s something there I need to sit with.</p>

<p>Anyway, that’s where I’m at. Tired. Reflective. Trying.</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="journal" /><category term="journal" /><category term="worship" /><category term="writing" /><category term="poetry" /><category term="diet" /><category term="reflection" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Running into Sunday with absolutely zero sleep is a special kind of disorientation. I’m not sure how I managed to function, but I did. And somehow, the Lord’s Day worship and breaking of bread was good, peaceful, weighty, needed.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bits and Pieces and Bread</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Bits-and-Pieces-and-Bread/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bits and Pieces and Bread" /><published>2025-05-03T17:35:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-05-03T17:35:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Bits-and-Pieces-and-Bread</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Bits-and-Pieces-and-Bread/"><![CDATA[<p>It’s one of those days where everything I own seems to be in a different pile. Notes tucked into old folders, ideas scribbled on scraps I barely remember writing, photos scanned but never sorted, there’s just a little bit of everything and a whole lot of nowhere to put it.</p>

<p>I’ve been chipping away at deciding what’s worth keeping, what needs to be worked on, and what’s finally ready for the trash. You’d think after all this time I’d be better at staying organized, but then again, maybe that’s part of the charm. Or at least, that’s what I tell myself.</p>

<p>Somehow in the middle of all this, I’ve found myself juggling two writing projects and a couple of research tangents that feel like they’ve spiraled into full dissertations. If only this scattered brain could pay the bills, right? Hah.</p>

<p>The Island Gospel Conference is coming up in a couple weeks, weekend of the 17th. I tried going to a ministry meeting with a friend last night. Turns out it wasn’t on. We only figured that out after we got there. Made the best of it though, met up with someone else instead, grabbed some food, and had some genuinely good conversations. Sometimes plans falling through lead to better ones.</p>

<p>I’ve also been thinking about journaling lately. It’s something I’ve never been great at. I’ll go through spurts and stops, but I’m always glad when I have a record to look back on later. Not because I think anything I’ve done is all that remarkable, but just because it’s good to remember. These posts are kind of like a public journal. I’ve kept private ones, too. Some are still around. Some probably got tossed in one of those cleaning frenzies. That’s okay.</p>

<p>Anyway, time to get back to sorting and writing. Maybe I’ll actually finish something tonight, but first, Bible reading and getting myself ready for tomorrow’s worship and breaking of bread. Everything else can wait a bit.</p>

<p>Until next time.</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="journal" /><category term="journal" /><category term="projects" /><category term="photos" /><category term="writing" /><category term="gospel" /><category term="Bible" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It’s one of those days where everything I own seems to be in a different pile. Notes tucked into old folders, ideas scribbled on scraps I barely remember writing, photos scanned but never sorted, there’s just a little bit of everything and a whole lot of nowhere to put it.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Getting Back Into Things</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Getting-Back-Into-Things/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Getting Back Into Things" /><published>2025-04-30T02:30:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-30T02:30:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Getting-Back-Into-Things</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Getting-Back-Into-Things/"><![CDATA[<p>Today felt like one of those quiet resets, not because anything grand happened, but because a few things finally moved forward.</p>

<p>For one, I got back on a bike again. It’s been years. My legs remembered how (mostly), but that seat has no mercy. Felt like I pedaled for five minutes and had earned an ice pack and a nap. But it’s a start. The plan isn’t distance or speed right now it’s <em>consistency</em>.</p>

<p>I also took some time to clean up this site, just a bunch of small updates here and there. Little style tweaks, layout fixes, improved tagging. I want this to be something I can build on slowly, not something that gets away from me like blogs in the past.</p>

<p>That goes for my Obsidian vault too. It got overgrown, bloated with folders and tags and items I wasn’t really using. Today was the start of a trim-back. Reorganizing and deleting. I’m trying to return it to a place where I can write and reflect, not just manage a maze.</p>

<p>To balance things out, I started a rewatch of <em>Doctor Who,</em> back to the Ninth Doctor and all the leather-jacket nostalgia. There’s something nice about returning to stories that once felt like home.</p>

<p>And of course, I kept up with my Bible reading schedule. Today’s portion was:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Leviticus 23</strong> About the feasts of the Lord, which were always more than calendar events, they were reminders of who He is.</li>
  <li><strong>Psalm 80</strong> A cry for restoration, written from the ache of distance and the hope of mercy.</li>
  <li><strong>Matthew 21</strong> The entry into Jerusalem and the clearing of the temple; a shift in tone and pace as the cross drew closer.</li>
</ul>

<p>Not a bad day, really. Nothing flashy. But a quiet kind of progress.</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="personal" /><category term="site-update" /><category term="daily-life" /><category term="obsidian" /><category term="biking" /><category term="doctor-who" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Today felt like one of those quiet resets, not because anything grand happened, but because a few things finally moved forward.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Website Rant</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Website-Rant/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Website Rant" /><published>2025-04-29T01:45:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-29T01:45:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Website-Rant</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Website-Rant/"><![CDATA[<p>Let’s be honest, some days the world feels a little broken.</p>

<p>Not in the big dramatic "end of everything" way, but in the small stupid things: slow websites, confusing paperwork, people who block store aisles…</p>

<p>Today’s minor frustration was just trying to get this blog fully set up. Tiny tweaks turning into small problems. But you know what? I got there.</p>

<p>Sometimes you just have to rant a little, then get back to it.</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="Rants" /><category term="rant" /><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Let’s be honest, some days the world feels a little broken.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Projects I’m Thinking About</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Projects-Im-Thinking-About/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Projects I’m Thinking About" /><published>2025-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Projects-Im-Thinking-About</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Projects-Im-Thinking-About/"><![CDATA[<p>Here’s a few things on my mind lately:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Expanding this blog little by little.</li>
  <li>Finding a way to organize my older writings and poems.</li>
  <li>Building some templates to aid my personal Bible study.</li>
  <li>??? Things</li>
</ul>

<p>Some of these will happen. Some might get abandoned. But that’s life, right?</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="Projects" /><category term="projects" /><category term="ideas" /><category term="planning" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Here’s a few things on my mind lately:]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Why I Write (Even When I’m Not Sure)</title><link href="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Why-I-Write/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Why I Write (Even When I’m Not Sure)" /><published>2025-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Why-I-Write</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://atrion.github.io/blog/blog/Why-I-Write/"><![CDATA[<p>Writing has always been a strange thing for me.</p>

<p>Sometimes I write because I feel like I have something to say. Sometimes I write just because the page is there, and it’s empty, and it feels wrong to leave it blank.</p>

<p>I don’t know where this site will go. I don’t even know what exactly it will become. But I’m starting it because I want to try. To share. To build. To maybe say something that matters, even if it’s just to myself.</p>

<p>We’ll see where it leads.</p>]]></content><author><name>Atrion Darnay</name></author><category term="Personal" /><category term="writing" /><category term="personal" /><category term="beginning" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Writing has always been a strange thing for me.]]></summary></entry></feed>